Guide to the Stanley Reeves Plummer Papers 1943-2000
Whitman College and Northwest Archives
Stanley Reeves Plummer Collection
1943-2000
Whitman College and Northwest Archives 345 Boyer Avenue Walla Walla, WA 99362 Archives@whitman.edu https://library.whitman.edu/archives/
Plummer, Stanley
WCMss.036
3.2 linear feet 5 boxes
This collection consists of assorted musical scores, posters, programs for recitals and other musical performances, notes from lectures to music classes, and newspaper clippings from the papers of Whitman music professor Stanley Plummer.
Collection is open for research.
Donated to the Whitman College and Northwest Archives by John (Jack) Pelo on June 20, 2006. The accession number is 2006-008.
Stanley Reeves Plummer was a Whitman College musical performer and educator. From 1950 until his retirement in 1981, he taught numerous Whitman students piano, organ, harpsichord, music theory and music history.
After retirement, he continued to perform, including a traditional pre-Halloween performance as he provided organ accompaniment to such silent horror films as "The Hunchback of Notre Dame", "Phantom of the Opera", and "The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari".
Professor Plummer also served the local Walla Walla community, playing for school graduations, weddings and other events. He performed with the Spokane Symphony, the Utah Symphony, the Oregon Symphony, and the Walla Walla Symphony and chamber orchestras. He also served as harpsichordist and director of music for the Ashland Shakespearean Festival in the 1950s.
The collection of Stanley R. Plummer includes assorted musical scores, posters, programs for recitals and other musical performances, notes from lectures to his music classes, and newspaper clippings.
Whitman College
Music; Music
- Air Force certificate, Papers, and clippings, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Whitman Archives Newsletter, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Whitman College Bulletin, 1953, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Photographs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- University of Southern California transcripts and summer teaching, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Catholic University of America 60th Annual Commencement Program, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- AGO Charterer, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Holthramp Organ papers, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- St. Paul's Church contract and papers, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Music from "The Coronation of Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II", 1953 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1943-1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Whitman correspondence and papers, Various (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Church correspondence and papers, 1945-1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Copyright papers, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Survey of the French Technique of organ playing, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Orchestration, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Mus 51: Class on Music History, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- History and Literature of Music – Boyden, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Hymnology Lecture, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Modern Music Class Papers, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Modern Music Class Papers, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Modern Music Class Papers, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Papers from Black Leather Binder – Class notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Hammond Organ Master Class, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Sound recording tape, Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Richard Feliciano – litany, Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Daniel Pinkham – "See That You Love One Another", Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Richard Feliciano, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Musical Tragedy Script – "A Potent Cultural Wallop", Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Organ Books and Musical Guide, Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
- AGO Music Magazine, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Recital Programs, Various (Box 1, Folder 33)
- AGO programs, 1955, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Whatcom Symphony Orchestra papers and programs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Acoustics of Cordiner Hall, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Harpsichord material, Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Roosevelt organ papers, Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Purchase order for Cordiner Hall organ, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Score for "Walla Walla Is My Home Town", 1948 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Clippings, Undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Mildred Weston Plummer – Funeral Program, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Albert Schweitzer photo and magazine article, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Scores, Lists, Undated (Box 2-4)
- Posters, Undated (Box 4, Box Flat files 1)
- Bibliographic Index, Card File, Undated (Box 5)